Inventory of the San Francisco Public Library collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Great Britain Foreign Office European War Documents, 1914-1918 (Box 4)
  - "Correspondence Between H.M. Government and the U.S. Ambassador Respecting the Treatment of Prisoners of War and Interned Civilians in the United Kingdom and German Respectively,", 1915
  - "Correspondence with the U.S. Ambassador Respecting the Execution of Miss Cavell at Brussels,", 1915
  - "Correspondence with the U.S. Ambassador Respecting the Treatment of British Prisoners of War and Interned Civilians in Germany,", 1915
  - "Memorandum of the German Government in Regard to Incidents Alleged to Have Attended the Destruction of a German Submarine and its Crew by H.M. Auxiliary Cruiser 'Baralong' on August 19, 1915, and Reply of H.M. Government Thereto,", 1916
  - "Statement of the Measures Adopted to Intercept the Sea-Borne Commerce of Germany,", 1916
  - "Selection from Papers Found in the Possession of Captain Von Papen, Late German Military Attache at Washington, Falmouth,", 1916
  - "Further Correspondence with the German Government Respecting the Incidents Alleged to Have Attended the Sinking of a German Submarine and Its Crew by H.M. Auxiliary Cruiser 'Baralong,'", 1916
  - "Further Correspondence with the U.S. Ambassador Respecting the Safety of Alien Enemies Repatriated from India on the S.S. 'Golconda,'", 1916
  - "Memorandum Presented by H.M. Government and the French Government to Neutral Governments Regarding the Examination of Parcels and Letter Mails,", 1916
  - "Report by the Government Committee on the Treatment by the Enemy of British Prisoners of War Regarding the Conditions Obtaining at Wittenberg Camp During the Typhus Epidemic of 1915,", 1916
  - "Sworn Statement by Horst von der Goltz, Alias Bridgeman Taylor,", 1916
  - "Further Correspondence Between H.M. Government and the U.S. Government Respecting the Rights of Belligerents,", 1916
  - "Correspondence with the U.S. Ambassador Respecting the Transfer to Switzerland of British and German Wounded and Sick Combatant Prisoners of War,", 1916
  - "Report by Doctor A.E. Taylor on the Conditions of Diet and Nutrition in the Internment Camp at Ruhleben Received Through the U.S. Ambassador,", 1916
  - "Correspondence Respecting the Employment of British and German Prisoners of War in Poland and France Respectively,", 1916
  - "Further Correspondence Respecting the Conditions of Diet and Nutrition at the Internment Camp at Ruhleben,", 1916
  - "Note Addressed to the U.S. Ambassador Regarding the Examination of Parcels and Letter Mails,", 1916
  - "Correspondence with the U.S. Ambassador Regarding the Relief of Allied Territories in the Occupation of the Enemy,", 1916
  - "Further Correspondence Respecting the Conditions of Diet and Nutrition in the Internment Camp at Ruhleben and the Proposed Release of Interned Civilians,", 1916
  - "Further Correspondence with the U.S. Ambassador Respecting the Treatment of British Prisoners of War and Interned Civilians in Germany,", 1916
  - "Collective Note Addressed to the Greek Government by the French, British, and Russian Ministers, and the Reply of the Greek Government,", 1916
  - "Correspondence with the Swedish Minister on the Subject of the Detention by the Swedish Government of the British Transit Mail to Russia as a Reprisal for the Search of Parcels Mail by H.M. Government,", 1916
  - "Reports of Visits of Inspection Made by Officials of the U.S. Embassy to Various Internment Camps in the United Kingdom,", 1916
  - "Report on the Typhus Epidemic at the Gardelegen by the Government Committee on the Treatment by the Enemy of British Prisoners of War During the Spring and Summer of 1915,", 1916
  - "Further Correspondence Respecting the Proposed Release of Civilians Interned in the British and German Empires,", 1916
  - "Further Correspondece with the U.S. Ambassador Respecting the 'Trading with the Enemy (Extension of Powers) Act, 1915,'", 1916
  - "Correspondence with the Belgian Minister Respecting the Deportation of Belgians to Germany and the Forced Labor Imposed Upon Them by German Authorities,", 1916
  - "Further Correspondence Respecting the Proposed Release of Civilians Interned in the British and German Empires,", 1917
  - "Memorandum Addressed by the French and British Government to the U.S. Government Regarding the Examination of Parcels and Letter Mails,", 1917
  - "Despatch to H.M. Ambassador at Washington Respecting the Allied Note of January 10, 1917,"
  - "Further Correspondence with the U.S. Ambassador Respecting the Treatment of British Prisoners of War and Interned Civilians in Germany,", 1917
  - "Reports on the Treatment by the Germans of British Prisoners and Natives in German East Africa,", 1917
  - "Correspondence Respecting the Transit Traffic Across Holland of Materials Susceptible of Employment as Military Supplies,", 1917
  - "Report on the Transport of British Prisoners of War to Germany,", 1918
  - "Correspondence with the German Government Respecting the Death by Burning of J.P. Genower, Able Seaman, When Prisoner of War at Brandenberg Camp,", 1918
  - "Report on the Treatment by the Enemy of British Prisoners of War Behind the Firing Lines in France and Belgium,", 1918
  - "Agreement between the British and Ottoman Governments Respecting Prisoners of War and Civilians,", 1918
  - "Correspondence with the Netherlands Government Respecting the Requisitioning of Dutch Ships by the Associated Governments,", 1918
- Italian History Pamphlets, 1912, 1918-1919, 1926 (Box 4)
  - "Fascism and Freemasonry,", undated
  - "Italy: What She Was, What She Is, What She Will Become,", 1919
  - "The Opera Nazionale Balilla,", undated
  - "Fiume--The Superlatively Italian City,", 1919
  - "The Economic Revival of Italy,", 1918
  - "Italy and Abyssinia,", undated
  - "The Fascist Dictatorship,", 1926
  - "Italy's Civilizing Mission in Africa,", 1912
  - "What Italy is Doing for Islam in Africa,", undated
- Julian March, undated (Box 4)
- Julian March 2, Maps, undated (Box 4)
- Modern Greece Historical Pamphlets, 1918-1919, 1930, 1935 (Box 4)
  - "Venizelos Conference,", 1919
  - "Belgium and Greece,", undated
  - "The Vindication of Greek National Policy 1912-1917,", undated
  - "Italy and the Unredeemed Isles of Greece,", 1935
  - "Persecution of the Greeks in Turkey 1914-1918,", 1919
  - "The Question of Northern Epirus at the Peace Conference,", 1919
  - "Persecutions of the Greeks in Turkey Since the Beginning of the European War,", 1918
  - "Report of the Greek University Commission on the Atrocities and Devestations Committed by the Bulgarians in Eastern Macedonia,", 1919
  - "One Hundred Years of Greek Independence,", 1930
- Netherlands at War Pamphlets, 1944, undated (Box 5)
  - "The Five Days of Holland,", undated
  - "Ten Years of Japanese Burrowing in the Netherlands East Indies,", undated
  - "From Illiteracy to University,", undated
  - "Mining in the Netherlands East Indies,", 1944
- Netherlands Information Bureau, 1942-1944 (Box 5)
  - "The Netherlands East Indies Comes of Age,", undated
  - "Postwar Reconstruction of the Netherlands,", 1942
  - "The Netherlands East Indies and Japan,", 1942
  - "Education in the Netherlands,", 1942
  - "Intensive Rural Hygiene Work in the Netherlands East Indies,", undated
  - "Towards Economic Democracy in the Netherlands Indies,", undated
  - "Decorative Art in the Netherlands,", undated
  - "Resistance of the Churches in the Netherlands,", 1944
- Poland Pamphlets, 1944-1945 (Box 5)
  - "Workmen's Protective Legislation in Poland,", undated
  - "Poland Here Is the Record,", 1945
  - "An Appeal to Franklin Delano Roosevelt President of the United States of America on Behalf of Poland,", undated
  - "Program for People's Poland,", 1944
  - "The Economic Structure of Poland,", undated
- Polish Government Information Center, 1942-1945 (Box 5)
  - "Polish Amendments to the Dumbarton Oaks Proposal,", undated
  - "Past of Poland,", 1943
  - "The Truth About Poland,", undated
  - "First to Fight,", 1943
  - "The Polish Constitution of the Third of May, Poland's National Holiday,", undated
  - "Polish Constitution,", 1942
  - "Poland, Russian, and Our Honor,", 1945
  - "General Outline of Modern Poland's Economy,", 1944
  - "Eastern Poland, Its Historical, Etnographic, Economic, Political, and Cultural Background,", undated
  - "Russian-Polish Relations, Their Historical, Cultural, and Political Background,", undated
  - "Polish-German Relations in Pomerania and East Prussia,", 1944
- Polish History Pamphlets, 1919-1923, 1931-1932 (Box 5)
  - "A New Project for the Destruction of Russia or How Polish Tyrants Contemplate the Extermination of the Ukrainian Race,", 1919
  - "Polish Library of Facts No. I, Polish-German Relations,", 1931
  - "Polish Library of Facts No. II, The Situation in Southeastern Poland,", 1931
  - "Polish Library of Facts No. III, Polish and German Minorities in Their Relation of the League of Nations,", 1932
  - "In to Free Poland Via Germany,", 1920
  - "Imperialism in Reborn Poland,", 1920
  - "Weekly News Release Issued by the Polish Bureau of Information,", 1921-1922
  - "My Impressions of New Poland,", undated
  - "The Polish Corridor,", 1932
  - "The United States of Poland,", undated
  - "Report of European Technical Advisers Mission to Poland 1919-1922,", 1923
- Portugal Historical Pamphlets, 1933, 1936-1937 (Box 5)
  - "Political Constitution of the Portuguese Republic,", 1937
  - "Professor Oliveira Salazar's Record,", 1936
  - "The Portuguese in Modern Colonization,", 1933
- Prisons and Prisoners in the European War, 1913-1917 (Box 5)
  - "Reprisals Against Prisoners of War,", 1916
  - "Reports on British Prison-Camps in India and Burma,", 1917
  - "Turkish Prisoners in Egypt,", 1917
  - "Atrocities in Russian Prisons,", 1913
  - "The Treatment of Prisoners of War in England and Germany,", 1915
  - "Les Prisonniers Allemands au Maroc,", 1917
  - "Le Regime des Prisonniers de Guerre en France et en Allemagne au Regard des Conventions Internationales, 1914-1916,"
  - "German Prisoners in Great Britain,", undated
- Roumanian History Pamphlets, 1919-1920, 1933-1934 (Box 5)
  - "The Transylvania Problem,", 1920
  - "The Roumanian Question,", undated
  - "The Roumanian Nation and the Roumanian Kingdom,", undated
  - "The Banat Problem,", 1920
  - "The Justice of Rumania's Cause,", undated
  - "The Ethnical Minorities of Transylvania,", 1934
  - "Sicules et Roumains,", 1933
  - "The Union of Bessarabia with Her Mother-Country Roumania,", 1920
  - "What I Have Seen in Bessarabia,", 1919
  - "Chronology in the Most Important Events of the Life of Bessarabia,", 1920
  - "The Economic State of Bessarabia,", 1920
- Russian History and Government, 1920-1924, 1931 (Box 5)
  - "The Third Russia,", 1920
  - "The International Goal of Russian Communism,", 1931
  - "America's Attitude to Soviet Russia,", 1931
  - "Russia's Call to Humanity, 'Save Our Souls,' an Appeal to the Allies,", undated
  - "Russia's Part in the World War,", 1920
  - "Red Russia Revealed,", 1923
  - "The Agrarian Revolution in Russia,", 1924
  - "The Reasons for the Disintegration of the Russian Babylone,", 1920
- Russian Liberation Committee, 1918-1919, undated (Box 5)
  - "Russia Under the Bolsheviks,", undated
  - "Lenin's Fighting Force,", undated
  - "London Under the Bolsheviks,", undated
  - "Russia's Call to Humanity, 'Save Our Souls,' An Appeal to the Allies,", undated
  - "The Volunteer Army of Alexeiev and Denikin,", 1918
  - "The Spirit of the Russian Revolution,", 1919
  - "Memorandum on the Baltic Provinces Question,", undated
  - "Proletarian Culture,", undated
  - "Bolshevism in Russia Through British Eyes,", 1919
  - "Russia and England,", undated
  - "Tche-Ka, the Story of the Bolshevist Extraordinary Commission,", undated
  - "In the Shadow of Death,", undated
- Spanish Revolution Pamphlets, 1937 (Box 5)
  - "Spain's Struggle Against Anarchism and Communism,", undated
  - "No Pasaran (They Shall Not Pass),", 1937
  - "The Spanish Republic and the Causes of Counter-Revolution,", 1937
  - "Democracy! Which Brand, Stalin's or Jefferson's?,", undated
  - "Ayuda a Madrid,", 1937
- Ukraine, 1938-1944 (Box 6)
  - "Ukraine; Battle Ground for Freedom,", 1944
  - "The Ukrainian Cause on Radio Waves,", 1939
  - "Ukraine Under Hungarian, Polish, and Russian Occupations,", undated
  - "Ukraina: Europe's Greatest Problem,", 1939
  - "Ukraine: Population and Economy,", 1938
  - "Ukraine and Russia,", 1940
  - "Ukraine: An Atlas of Its Geography,", 1942
  - "Free Ukraine Is Vital to Lasting Peace,", undated
- Welfare Work in the European War, 1918-1923 (Box 6)
  - "American Library Association Library War Service,", 1920
  - "Soldiers, Sailors, and Books,", 1918
  - "Report to the Secretary of War on the Activities of Welfare Organizations,", undated
  - "War Service of the American Library Association: Books for the Men in Camp & Overseas,", 1918
  - "Report of the Conference on Moral and Religious Work in the Army,", 1923
  - "Books at Work,", undated
  - "Report of Hostess House Committee,", undated
  - "Young Women's Christian Association of the United States of America,", 1919
- Yugoslavia Historical Pamphlets, 1916-1933 (Box 6)
  - "Austro-Magyar Judicial Crimes. Persecutions of the Jugoslavs. Political Trials 1908-1916,", undated
  - "The Independence of Small Nations and the Extinction of Montenegro,", 1931
  - "Montenegro, the Crime of the Peace Conference,", 1922
  - "The Greatest Crime in History,", 1930
  - "L'universite Francaise et la Jeunesse Serbe,", 1919
  - "Los Procedimientos de Guerra de los Austro-Hungaros en Servia,", 1915
  - "The Dawn of Armageddon, or the Provocation by Serbia,", 1917
  - "Kosovo-Day,", undated
  - "Croatia, Bosnia and Herczegovina and the Serbian Claims,", 1916
  - "The Betrayal of Montenegro,", 1933
  - "Abridged Political History of Rieka (Fiume),", 1919